Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com
EPISODE 83
A time had come, brother, where
our paths departed.
You who were on the path of justice...
...and me who had a blind eye.
I made mistake.
I became unwary.
My blood is halal to you my brother.
Come on, brother.
Come on.
The only way appears to be on
the edge of my weapon, my Shiekh.
That is right.
It's on the edge of your weapon.
But it's not the weapon on your belly...
...that will wake Gündüz from sleep.
It's the mercy in your heart.
It's to forgive.
Even if he has done all of these things?
Human nature is tendentious
to make mistakes.
We're human beings.
The important thing is regretting.
Regretting and asking
Allah for forgiveness.
Do not preserve your
mercy from someone who...
...asks Allah for mercy.
Forgiving...
...is the tradition of Allah.
Let the government you dream of...
...grow with not only its
strength but with its mercy.
Forgive your brother.
One day, death will find us all.
But I will not take your life today.
You beg Allah.
So that he can forgive you.
I got set up in a dirty scheme, brother.
When I wanted to do good...
...I became the tool of the tyrants.
If you can see that you fell...
...then why don't you stand up, brother?
Why do you send the alps to Geyhatu?
Why do you try to destroy
the Turkmen tribes?
I knew you would be in my way, Osman.
I knew it.
I would pray...
...something would happen
to me on the road...
...so that I could not
achieve my objective.
Look,...
...my prayer was not unanswered, brother.
It came true.
Your intent and action
are different, brother.
Geyhatu was going to burn the monastery,
the willow, and the entire tent.
To stop him...
...to stop him...
...I gave Geyhatu a promise.
No Kayı,...
...no monastery...
...no willow...
...they don't stand against martyrdom.
But just because they could live...
...you did not care for them.
I made a lot of mistakes, brother.
A lot.
I can't count.
There are so many.
İNEGÖL CASTLE
Mingiyan. Mongols came to my
castle a bunch of times before.
Yet,...
...Osman killed them every time.
But now, we're friends.
We're together against Osman, right?
Geyhatu warned me about you.
Don't be afraid if he draws his
weapon but be afraid if he speaks.
So, shut up Nikola.
"Don't be afraid if he draws his weapon
but be afraid if he speaks." That's nice.
Geyhatu is a good judge of character.
Nikola, I will see your
soldiers, swords, horses...
I will review the army
you'll give to Geyhatu.
You'll do all of this
Mingiyan, I mean all of it.
But before that, I got
a little surprise for you.
Soldier!
Coghatuz
Nikola,
I knew you were not trustworthy.
You know everything Logotuz
Maybe you know where Osman is as well.
I will not punish you today.
You will obey me.
You'll do whatever I ask.
I am at your command Osman Bey.
Don't you get this out of your head.
No one will know.
You'll keep commanding
like a bey at the tent.
I will kill the ones...
...who had tricked you.
You will bring me Geyhatu.
I will get on his neck like a wolf.
Now you go to him...
...so that he doesn't figure out our plan.
May Allah bless you, my brother!
May Allah bless you!
Horses!
Go back to the tent!
Today, the blood of the tyrant
will shed, not the Turks'.
Just the way I want.
So, you're not going to speak now?
Alright, suit yourself.
No!
I like burning people.
Even if I gave you Osman's location,
you would still kill me.
If Osman lives...
...we'll have a chance to
get vengeance on you.
Do you see how he trusts Osman?
If you speak, you may stay alive.
Isn't that right?
What we need is Osman's location...
This fool can live the
rest of his life stamped.
Come on!
Tell us Osman's location, come on!
You wanted this.
Alright, alright, alright!
I'll tell you!
Osman and Koses are
hiding at Kuzgun Hill.
Huh, now you gave us
the information we wanted.
Untie him. Untie him.
I got one more surprise for you.
I knew you would do this.
You know everything but...
...do it anyways.
You are an ignoble man, Nikola.
And always live that way.
But, I will live.
Soldier!
That's it!
Geyhatu likes this.
Argus!
Get an army with you!
I want Koses and Osman!
Hold!
My bey, I waited at
Kurtboğazı as you wished.
They found me and gave me your deposit.
Beys inform us that they
have accepted our invitation.
Thank Allah!
Praise be!
Now go and prepare for a feast
Now,...
...now we're going to flare up
the fire of rebellion inside them.
Weapons will not be in their
holsters until these lands are revived!
Geyhatu will regret not
coming but being born.
Come on!
Kumral!
Hide!
Allah, Allah!
Master Davut, I did not think
it would be this powerful.
Not only did it explode...
...but I also put the parts remaining
from the weapons inside.
They'll stick on the ones
around it like arrows.
Those damn Geyhatu dogs.
Before those dogs, you
were going to get me!
Did you plan this?
That's right Kumral Abdal
It's a really good plan.
It will drop a bunch of them without
even drawing our weapons.
Shepherd is a dervish.
Does a dervish ever stay out of trouble?
Of course not.
Shepherd's seclusion is because
of his preparedness for war.
Instead of throwing this with its fuse...
...can we throw it with a catapult?
But,...
...what if it explodes the moment it hits.
It would do damage ten times
more than a cannon can.
But it needs power for it to
explode the moment it hits.
I'll look out for that.
Praise be!
He won't leave a wall not demolished.
We'll not just demolish them...
...if we're going to demolish a wall...
...we'll build inside.
If we're going to demolish a wall...
...we'll revive it.
Also, what is demolishing for?
To build back better.
I'll look for it.
A man without hands is
prey to the animals in nature.
This is what the fools who
cannot protect the fire deserve.
It seems Rogatus was
not a man, just like them.
He could not endure the torture.
He said where Osman will be.
Where will Osman's head be?
Osman had kept changing his location...
...but he has a meeting with
Rogatus tomorrow night.
He'll be at Kuzgun hill.
Make your preparations Mingiyan.
Kuzgun Hill will be hell for Osman.
Yes, Commander Geyhatu!
Gündüz Bey is here, Commander Geyhatu.
But he is alone. Doesn't
have his alps with him.
Let him come.
Yes, sir!
Where are the alps?
How could Gündüz come to
me without keeping his word?
My bey, as you wished, I shifted some
of the Seljuk soldiers behind the tent.
But the ones in the
entrance will not move.
You got one more duty Erdu Alp.
When the night falls...
...get as many Seljuk soldiers
out of the tent as you can.
We'll handle the rest.
Yes, my bey!
My bey,...
...will we trust Güzdüz Bey?
Punishment of treachery is clear.
If he betrays us...
...he'll pay the price.
Circumstances of traitors
are clear, Gündüz.
You did it with your hands...
...and pay it with your neck.
Osman will make you pay for
what you have done eventually.
Will you be Abel or Cain?
Will you turn your back on your brother?
If you side with Geyhatu, power,
office, position will be yours.
Where are my Alps, Gündüz?
Alps are a whole, Geyhatu
Where are they?
At the tent.
You were going to bring your alps...
...army was going to head
towards lord castles.
Why are alps at the tent, Gündüz?
I know Osman,..
...I keep them at the tent for the
possibility of a raid on the road.
The weapons of my alps
will spill blood for you Geyhatu.
Be sure of that.
Following my orders will keep
all of you alive Gündüz Bey.
Or I'll burn all of you alive.
I gave you a word...
...and I'll keep it.
Have no doubt.
I don't doubt...
...I destroy!
What about Osman?
Is there any word from him?
Osman is cautious.
He stays at a different
location each night.
But I'm very close, I'll find him
Then don't stay here, go and find Osman...
...and when I want your
alps, bring them here!
May Allah bless you, Geyhatu!
I'll do what you say.
No one lies when death is this close...
...Ragatus said it right...
Get the servants ready!
We will go to Kuzgun Hill tomorrow.
I will rip off Osman's liver.
Get out!
I wish it was warmer.
Osman Bey is seen around the tent.
Get him! Quickly!
Let's go!
Osman! That's Osman!
Let's get him!
Get him! Come on!
Soldiers.
What's wrong?
Is it tight my boy?
Osman?
Bala!
- Osman?
- Longing is over.
Thank goodness!
Praise be!
How does he kick like that?
His time is near.
It's near, Osman.
As time get's closer, I get more excited.
Don't you worry!
We'll embrace him
soon if Allah permits.
If Allah permits.
What about...
...you just said, my boy.
These clothes...
...is it a boy.
I feel so.
- My son?
- Mother.
I could not believe it
when I got the word.
Welcome, my dear boy!
Happy to be here, mother!
Happy to be here!
Welcome my bey!
How did you come?
I hope Gündüz Bey or
Seljuk soldiers hear this.
My alps removed the alps from the tent.
Do not worry at all.
Gündüz Bey knows I'm here.
What are you saying, son?
How come?
Did Gündüz understand his mistake?
It was late but...
...Gündüz Bey's blind eyes
have opened a little bit.
He saw Vizier's treachery.
Thank goodness, he saw the truth!
How could we trust him after
all that he has done, my bey?
Will, we just forget what he
has put us and the tent through?
Of course, we won't.
He'll pay for what he has done.
Justice will be served.
What are you going to do to Gündüz, son?
The end of the traitors is clear, mother.
All this time...
...you did not care for the throne...
...or for the fame.
Now, look at what have
you gotten yourself into?
How will you look at your ancestor's
face on judgment day, Gündüz Bey?
Above all...
...how are you going to
forgive yourself, Gündüz Bey?
May I come in, my bey?
Come in.
Gündüz Bey, beys are coming.
Let them come.
- Selam Alaykum, my bey!
- Selam Alaykum!
Alaykum Selam!
What's wrong, my bey?
What's wrong Gündüz Bey?
What is the rush?
There is nothing wrong.
It is time to leave the
throne to the best.
What is he talking about?
Who is that?
Why is dressed like that?
- Who is that?
- I don't know.
I wonder who that is.
Who could it be?
Osman Bey is here.
- It's Osman Bey!
Osman Bey is here!
- Welcome, my bey!
- Welcome!
Servants of my tent...
...excuse me!
I woke from sleep.
Turk's bey...
...Turk's soldier...
...has been famous for his loyalty...
...since Mete Khan.
When his bey says something he does it.
He dies if he says so.
When the head wolf departs...
...he follows him until death!
The thickness of the wolf's neck...
...is because of handling
his own business.
You count what Vizier has
given you as a conquest.
Whoever sits on somebody else's
property, loses their freedom.
Beys! You have not become beys for Kayı...
...but servants for Vizier.
Osman Bey, ask us to kill, we'll
kill, ask us to die, we'll die.
We're only servants for Allah.
The ones who fall into heedlessness, the
ones who commit cruelty should be...
...stopped with your hands if you can't do
that then you warn them with your mouth.
If not then, you will use your heart
to hate them.
If you cannot do that...
...then...
...your humanity finishes.
Some of you would rather die in sleep...
...than to die in battle.
Some of you are sheep in wolfskin.
The ones who obeyed Gündüz Bey will pay.
My bey, we just didn't want
the throne to be vacant.
We're with you.
Sometimes stopping is
better than going off a clip.
If you're with me, you'll
accept your punishment.
You all fell into heedleness.
And you'll pay for that.
- Couldn't you find him, brother?
- We couldn't find him, brother.
I'll tell Gündüz Bey we couldn't find him.
I'll tell Güzndüz Bey, brother.
It is my duty Boran Alp.
Brother, you'll get your bones broken.
Move aside!
Why don't you want
us to get inside the tent?
Or, is Osman Bey in the tent?
Come on, brother!
Come on!
Surrendering is not in our tradition.
Kayı Tent will fight
till its last breathe.
The fire of rebellion will flare up
in the heart of the Turkmen tribes.
We will flare up the fire in these parts.
Excuse us, Osman Bey!
Gündüz Bey did a lot to
save us from this fire.
And you still talk about fire.
We will flare the fire in Kayı.
Anyone who doesn't want
to burn should go, Varul Bey.
Must we burn, Osman Bey?
Can't we live in prosperity as well?
Everyone wants to be rich.
Anybody who wants to lose their freedom...
...can go spend someone else's money.
Now,...
...take your kid and hatun
and get out of here.
Go somewhere you'll be rich.
The one who has a love for money
in their heart instead of courage...
...is not one of us.
- What are you...
- Get out!
Anyone whose heart hadn't darkened when
the Turk is oppressed, can stay with us.
If anyone has something to say, say it.
My bey, you say courage,
and may Allah bless you!
But you are allied with Nikola...
...they killed a lot of our valiants.
Don't worry at all.
After we defeat Geyhatu...
...we'll make Nikola pay for
all the blood he has shed.
My bey, Nikola knows this as well.
He won't wait for Geyhatu
to go to stab us in the back.
Have no worry.
Emperor Andronikos
gave me Nikola's bridles.
He can't do anything to us.
If anyone has doubt...
...they can follow Varul Bey.
There is no turning back.
Government comes before all!
Mother is it true that
Osman Bey has come?
Is he with Gündüz?
Mother, may Allah protect him...
...will he do something to Gündüz?
It's where words fail my girl.
It's up to Osman Bey.
What can I say Ayşe?
When you took care of my Orhan,
he separated me from my child.
It's not time to speak out.
Let's hope for the best for him.
What did Geyhatu say?
He asked about the alps I promised him.
And I told them that
they're all at the tent.
Did he just ask that?
He asked about you as well.
I told him that I didn't know where
you were and that I was after you.
He did not suspect anything.
He won't.
You got covered in mud with the traitor.
You ate with the traitor.
Of course, he'll not suspect anything.
Whatever you say, you are right, brother.
But I was never cruel like them.
I just got tricked by them.
There is no difference between the cruel
and the one who follows him, brother.
You talked about salvation before...
...now you talk about getting tricked.
Don't get tricked brother.
Don't believe their words, brother.
A Muslim must be awake.
A Muslim must know to learn his lesson.
You did not draw a lesson from uncle?
Tell me.
You did not draw a lesson from him.
You got tricked by them and...
...made yourself and
the tent their servant.
Heedlessness is haram to us.
The punishment of the ones who
fall into heedlessness is clear.
It is clear.
For that reason, my blood is
halal for you, brother.
I believe that you are awaken now.
Ertuğrul Ghazi's son, Gündüz Bey.
Your pardon is not at me anymore.
I spare your life, brother.
But...
but your treason to our brotherhood,
our laws and customs won't be forgotten.
As long as this body carries this head,
I won't forget nor forgive what I did.
If you do...
don't return to the tribe, brother.
Boran.
Yes, my bey.
Tell the ladies.
They should lay a table.
As you order, my bey.
Söğüt
Salam Alaikum.
Alaikum Salam.
I was expecting you, Güngör Bey.
Karamanoğulları are revolting.
Things are getting complicated.
Emperor Androkinos gathered
his commanders.
Everyone is taking a position.
What's the cause of this chaos?
It's Geyhatu who I sharpen
my blade behind.
All his shields are raised against
his enemies, Güngör Bey.
I'm his enemy in disguise.
Why are you waiting for this long?
Why is Geyhatu still alive, Alemşah?
Geyhatu is the greatest trouble
in these lands.
The one who saves the lands from the
trouble becomes the owner of them.
The one who kills Geyhatu becomes
the sultan.
I think that my bey should do such
a sacred thing.
Good.
I have my brother's seal.
So, it's my duty to destroy
Geyhatu.
I'll make a throne out of Geyhatu's
bones for my brother.
Once the borders are saved from Geyhatu,
everyone will be loyal to my bey.
While I'm digging a grave for
Geyhatu...
you'll have another job, Alemşah.
My Orhan...
Mashallah to my lion!
Come on.
Light follows a dark night, son.
Thank Allah, mother.
Thank Allah, we are united again.
We haven't laid such a table for
so long, my bey.
We missed it.
True. We missed it.
But you acted my bravely than
men.
Thank you.
It'll be harder from now on.
If we stay united, we can overcome
them all.
As long as we have you,
we can overcome anything.
Thank you.
It's not the first time I'm separated
from my family.
But...
this was a lot harder.
I wouldn't have worries back
then...
I would trust that my brother
would protect my loved ones.
Brother.
Ask for forgiveness from the ones you
hurt and bled.
I trusted the tongue of the devil...
what I've done keeps burning
my heart.
In this short time, I made you suffer
a lot.
I can't look at any of you.
All I can do is ask for forgiveness.
Mother.
Mother, you too.
Give me your blessing.
It is never too late to repent.
Now, your duty is harder.
It's time to rebuild.
If Orhan was hurt, then you wouldn't
be forgiven.
You have my blessing, Gündüz Bey.
If one of us were hurt, Gündüz Bey...
But, like our mother says...
thank Allah, we are safe and sound.
You have my blessing.
Thank Allah, my mother is well.
Thank Allah, Gündüz Bey.
Thank Allah.
Enjoy your meals now.
With the name of Allah.
Osman the dark doesn't know
his limits.
Now, he informs the beys about
gathering a council.
I'm the ruler of these borders.
The beys are using my gold...
and they are going to Osman's
council.
Look at this!
I'm speaking my bey's information.
This is your job, Alemşah.
As long as I have his tribe even...
the council he'll form won't
pose any threat.
I hold the wires of his brother
who sits on the throne.
But it's my responsibility to behead
Osman and those beys.
I'll destroy Geyhatu and you'll
destroy the revolting beys.
There should be no obstacle in my
brother's way to sultanate.
How do you plan to kill Geyhatu?
Did my bey send an army?
No. I will do it personally.
An army protects Geyhatu.
How will you do it?
With mind, Alemşah.
With mind.
Mind is a greater weapon than all
the armies combined.
I'll hit Geyhatu from where
he doesn't expect it.
Osman is also looking for away to
kill Geyhatu.
Be quick.
Alright.
Soldier!
Summon Konur.
Cerkutay.
My bey.
Mother.
With Allah's order...
and our prophet's wish,
peace be upon him...
I ask for my sister Aygül...
to my brave Cerkutay.
Cerkutay, tell me.
Will you take good care of my daughter?
I will, mother.
Then, you have my permission.
But...
there is no point in waiting.
Ladies, prepare...
we'll have a wedding tomorrow.
Let's do it.
My bey.
Am I allowed to?
It's yours.
Allah Allah!
Allah!
Stop, you mad man!
Cerkutay.
Allah!
Control yourself.
There are soldiers outside.
Did it fit, brother?
Mashallah, brother.
Brothers!
In the evening...
no one should be hungry at my
wedding.
Don't worry, brother.
But...
let's make sure
you are fed...
the rest is easy.
No, no, no, no.
Come on.
Allow me, brother.
What are you looking at?
Come on.
Kumral Abdal!
This way!
This is the end of our friendship.
But we are separating for a
holy cause.
I'm not sad.
Why should I be?
You will be a food for two lovers'
wedding!
Is there a better fate?
There can't be.
It'll be sacrificed for love.
Mashallah!
Come on.
With the name of Allah.
Brothers!
I don't want any problem at my wedding!
All power to your elbows, brothers!
Brother, how does it taste?
It's good.
It's rich in meat, right?
It's rich in meat as long as
you don't eat them, brother.
I won't.
Allahu Aqbar.
There is no god but Allah.
Cerkutay, stop.
You'll eat it all!
I'm still hungry, brother!
I eat but I'm still hungry!
It's excitement, Cerkutay.
It's excitement, Akça Dervish.
Stop, Cerkutay.
Brother Boran, take him away or there
will be no food left.
Cerkutay, come, brother.
Look, brother.
The secret of love is patience.
The end of patience is peace.
May Allah give you happiness.
Amin, Kumral Abdal.
Amin!
What is this excitement, brother?
We are excited, brother!
Leave my brother alone.
He waited a lot.
He is excited.
Let them have their fun!
Let them!
I'm with my Aygül!
Let them have as much as
fun as they want!
Let me eat a little more.
Cerkutay, let's go.
Let's go.
Come on.
Before you, I would come here
with Karayel.
Now, you are my companion.
These lands...
will be a part of the country we'll
form for order.
But...
but not only the lands
that my eyes can see...
beyond the plains and mountains too!
I'll spread Allah's 99 names to all
over the world!
My Allah...
my Allah!
Who are you?
What do you want?
Move out of my way!
I don't seek evil, merchant.
I want to trade.
What are you carrying?
My goods aren't for sale.
Every merchant sells their goods
if the price is good.
If I owned the goods,
of course.
But I don't own them.
It's Geyhatu.
It won't do you good to meddle.
Not only your goods...
I want you, your animals
and these men.
I'll pay ten times the price.
We'll carry the goods together, merchant.
And I'll give you a thousand coins.
You'll take me into the quarters.
You'll have a thousand coins.
And you'll keep yourself alive, merchant.
There will be blood!
There will be a lot of blood!
Hell will come down to this world!
There is blood on great Geyhatu!
It's Osman's blood!
Tell me!
The blood of those who revolt
to Geyhatu.
Tell me about the skulls!
Tell me about the beheaded!
There are no heads over
the shoulders.
Geyhatu will win this war.
He'll control these lands.
Tell me! Is it just
these lands?
Spreading, just like blood...
Geyhatu's rule spreads into
the whole world!
First, these lands...
then, Argun Khan's throne...
then, the whole world!
The whole world!
We've been fighting for
a long time, Kosses.
Are you tired?
Never.
The men of our dynasty had fought
and died on the battlefield for centuries.
We don't get tired of war, Osman Bey.
On the contrary...
being close to death makes
me feel alive.
Death is always upon us.
Have you...
missed your castle?
I missed my castle as much as
you missed your throne.
It's time.
You can go to your throne.
Harmankaya Castle belongs to you.
Thank you for your help.
So, we are at the end of
this adventure.
Our unity was until getting
the castle.
Time will show that.
What about...
Gündüz Bey?
What is he saying
about that?
He'll visit you at the castle.
You can ask him yourself.
I see, Osman.
I'm grateful for everything.
If you want to feel that
you are alive...
we can fight shoulder to shoulder
again.
Thank you, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
These are Geyhatu's provisions.
Go.
Why are you late?
Answer me!
Bandits attacked us on the road.
Why didn't they kill you?
We told them the provisions
were Geyhatu's.
No one walks to their death.
Stop!
There are there!
Rebellion to the State of Seljuk means
death.
Osman is a traitor who even tried to kill
the Sultan.
You will kill him and those who help him.
For the State of Seljuk.
Vizier...
...everyone we will ambush is Turkmens.
Are you sure?
When did your duty become questioning
your master, Konur?
Those who seem loyal to me but work with
Osman are traitors.
The traitor cannot be separated as
Turkmen or Bey.
Don't leave a single one alive!
I am coming for you, Osman!
Do you remember, Osman Bey?
You told me something.
You said, no matter how you perceive us...
...we perceive you as one of us.
How did you know I was one of you?
From the way you ride your horse.
Does anyone who is not one of us
ride a horse like this?
Thank you.
You must know that...
...since the day I am one of you, I have
lived in peace.
Thank you.
My Bey!
Osman!
Ambush!
Are you all right, my Vizier?
How did this happen, Konur?
Search everywhere!
It obviously was an ambush.
Let's get you out of the woods first.
There may be another trap.
Osman will pay for this.
And thank you, Konur.
My duty is to protect you, my Vizier.
Osman, how do you know about,
my every move?
Vizier Alemşah found out about where you
will have an assembly with the Beys.
He plans an ambush in the morning.
No other but the Beys knew
about the assembly.
Then there must be a traitor
among the Beys.
My Bey, I give you this information but
the Vizier's suspicions...
...are increasing each day.
We fail every move of him.
First, we will dispel the doubt of
the Vizier.
Then, you will find that traitor.
I will set the trap.
You will save the Vizier.
We can lure him to the trap but...
why aren't we killing him, Osman Bey?
I told you in the beginning.
Information is everything.
Vizier won't die.
He is a familiar enemy.
You are with him.
We know about his every move.
Now...
...now we will finish Geyhatu.
As you order, my Bey.
Soldiers, bring the horses.
We are returning to Söğüt.
Osman...
...you are only raising your suffering.
I will hang you and those rebellious beys
at the entry of Söğüt.
Mashallah to my girl!
You look so beautiful.
Thanks to Allah I could see these days.
Mother...
...you never let me feel the absence of
my parents.
You brought me out of the darkness.
You lightened my way.
How can I ever repay you?
You can repay me by being happy.
Come on, enough of talking.
Come on!
Bring her veil.
Here, Selcen Mother.
Let's put it on.
Praise be!
Come here.
In the name of Allah.
Can we come in, Selcen Mother?
Wait, girl. Don't get excited.
Come in, Cerkutay.
What is that in your hand, son?
Cerkutay?
Cerkutay!
What is that in your hand, son?
Honey.
For what?
Mother...
...you said for sweet talking you need
honey...
...when you were preparing Mari Hatun's
dowry.
This crazy girl needs much of it.
Thus, I brought honey.
You did well, son.
Mashallah to my valiant!
-For sweet talking!
-Amen!
Here you go.
Mother, give her more.
We did, son!
What do we need for intelligence, mother?
Let's feed him that.
Girl!
Look, mother!
It wasn't enough.
You feed her this.
I'll go find a hive.
Don't, son!
Now I will make you eat!
Mother!
Get out before I change my mind, Cerkutay!
Come on!
Get out!
Come on, get out!
I don't need sweet talking.
I love you like this.
-Son, get out!
-Mother.
Come on!
Aygül, daughter of Dündar...
...do you take son of Cengiz, Cerkutay...
...as your husband by giving you a hundred
dirhams of gold and ten sheep as gifts?
I do.
-Do you?
-I do.
Son of Cengiz, Cerkutay...
...do you take...
...Aygül, daughter of Dündar as your wife?
I do.
-Do you?
-I do.
Do you witness?
We do.
May your marriage be blessed.
Amen.
Al Fatiha!
Come on.
Alps!
Take your swords out!
Come on!
Cerkutay alp is great!
-Also is his heart!
-What, brother?
What did he do for Aygül Hatun?
He brought apples from the other world!
But he ate them all himself!
For how long did he wait?
Too long!
But he met his dream!
Did he break any hearts?
Never!
He married Aygül Hatun!
Then, may Allah grant them happiness!
Amen!
May you grow old together!
Brother.
Where are you going?
Boran!
Hit the lute!
As you order, my Bey!
We wintered in the land of Rum,
we committed a lot of good and evil.
Come, let's make peace,
if you remember, let's know.
Our horse is saddled,
we blew Alhamdulillah.
We blew Alhamdulillah.
We wintered in the land of Rum,
we committed a lot of good and evil.
We were resurrected, became spring,
we were startled, became a river
We flowed, we filled the sea,
we overflowed Alhamdulillah.
We overflowed Alhamdulillah.
We wintered in the land of Rum,
we committed a lot of good and evil.
Spring has come back,
we migrated Alhamdulillah.
We became slaves to the deed
you worshiped.
We were sluggish and raw,
we learned Alhamdulillah.
We learned Alhamdulillah.
We wintered in the land of Rum,
we committed a lot of good and evil.
Spring has come back,
we migrated Alhamdulillah.
We wintered in the land of Rum,
we committed a lot of good and evil.
Spring has come back,
we migrated Alhamdulillah.
We migrated Alhamdulillah.
Praise be!
When we get to our tribe,
we will throw our arrow...
...and build our home on the best place
of the tribe.
I hope.
You just return home safely.
We will do all of them one by one...
...my Cerkutay.
What did you say?
Did you say it to me?
I couldn't hear. Say it again.
Cerkutay!
-Welcome.
-Thank you.
Osman Bey is waiting for you.
-Where is the assembly?
-I couldn't understand this.
First, the place changed.
Now, you brought us to the woods.
Osman Bey doesn't do all this in vain.
You will find out when you meet him.
Where is Osman Bey?
Now I will take you to him.
But first...
...Alps.
Osman Bey's order. Cover the Bey's eyes.
Go to Söğüt at once.
Find Vizier Alemşah.
Convey my words to him.
Come on!
We will attack when...
...the poison takes effect.
Come on, to the horses!
Welcome, I am glad you came.
We are not welcome at all, Osman Bey.
What is this?
Why did you put us through
all the trouble?
I hope you have a reasonable excuse,
Osman Bey.
Bless your right.
But it is for precaution.
What precaution?
Isn't this assembly secret?
No other than the beys know about it.
We thought so.
But someone among us...
...informed the Vizier about the assembly
and the place.
Therefore...
...there is a traitor among us.
Who is it?
Who betrays at this time can have no
dignity.
How can there be a traitor among us?
I would protect you, Commander
Geyhatu.
Did we really need them?
They...
...die!
If I tell them to.
They don't ask questions like you...
...Mingiyan.
Mingiyan, what we need to prove is not
the value.
They only follow the orders.
You can't buy them...
...or deceive them.
Osman...
...I am bringing you the death!
With ninety-nine names of
Almighty Allah...
...who makes us be when he says be, and
fills our hearts with the light of faith.
In the name of Allah.
I wish we could have our assembly in the
Bey Tribe, in Söğüt.
But, you know the situation well.
My Bey, you say there is a traitor
among us.
But you still did the assembly.
Aren't you afraid of what the traitor
will hear?
On the contrary!
I am glad he will convey what we will
declare beforehand.
He should know.
He should know...
...what happens to a traitor.
Now...
...you all must have heard.
The tribes in the middle are rebelling.
Then what we must do...
...is uniting under that flag.
Thus, we will support the rebellions
in faraway tribes.
Osman Bey, Konya is listening to
every order of the Mongols.
Rebelling to Geyhatu means
rebelling to the State.
When was the last time you went to Konya,
Teymur Bey?
I just came from Konya.
Konya isn't listening to the Mongols.
Konya now belongs to the Mongols.
Is there a free state that we must fear...
...a rebellion?
You talk nice Osman Bey but...
...your recent policies reduced
all the tribe's strength.
What do we have that...
...we can rebel with?
We conducted that policy so that nothing
gets worse.
But there were those who believed
the tyrants.
Those who lost their ways.
Now the worse times came.
We are now in the end.
Now, the swords that are taken out...
...for the order of the world
are in charge.
There are experienced beys among you.
They know me very well and my father
Ertuğrul Gazi.
Thus, they don't say a word to me.
They do not object to anything.
They know that...
...Kayı never breaks his promise.
Now If there is anyone who is afraid of
rebellion, wants to escape the battle...
...he can wait to die in his tent.
I have one hundred tents in my tribe.
My tribe, my alps and my life...
...we are at your disposal.
Our way is...
...your way from now on, Osman Bey.
Thank you.
There are more soldiers to come...
...besides Geyhatu's army.
Argun Khan is sending
twenty thousand soldiers.
Osman, you knew I was coming!
But how?
Can I come in, my Vizier?
Come in, Konur.
You get out.
Güngör Bey poisoned the Nökers.
He is going after Geyhatu.
Geyhatu is going to the Kuzgun Hill.
Geyhatu!
Do you think I would give these lands to
the Mongols?
If there is a need for a leader, I will
be that leader.
You will burn in hell.
Your fire will be plenty because of the
slaughters you made.
My tribe has one hundred twenty tents,
Osman Bey.
Even if young people fight...
...only two hundred soldiers
will come out.
My horse is without saddle,
my arrow is without resentment.
Two hundred soldiers will fight with
honor beside us.
If Geyhatu passes us...
...he will destroy your tribe.
If you need it, both the sword
and the soldier will be found.
Master Davut.
Welcome.
Master Davut is preparing with his
blacksmiths...
...day and night.
We saw it all.
Thus, we made all the preparations.
Don't worry.
We have everything we need.
But...
...you must have heart, Beys!
You will encourage your hatuns,
your people.
You will be the strongest!
We came to make these lands home.
We have come to make Islam dominant
in these lands.
If we are to surrender without a fight
to the last drop of our blood...
...may the sky turn red!
Inshallah!
My tribe will provide five hundred
soldiers including the women.
I'm with you with three hundred horsemen
and two hundred pedestrians.
We are few...
...we don't fear death!
They must fear us!
We are with you, Osman Bey!
Thank you.
These lands are ours!
This place will be a home for those
who come friendly...
...and a grave for those
who come unfriendly.
May our battle be blessed!
Amen!
I am leaving now.
No, don't.
Don't.
You are my guests today.
There was a double assembly today.
Thus, we have a lot of meat and ayran.
Enjoy them.
But that traitor...
...will be found.
Now I am going to the battle.
Every sword I slash will come out of
this tent.
May your road be open, Osman Bey!
May your sword be sharp!
May your road be open and
your sword be sharp!
May your sword be sharp!
Thank you.
With my Allah's will, this will end today.
For the sake of the oppressed, my sword
will cut the neck of the oppressor!
May your road be open!
We will be praying for you!
May your sword be sharp, my Bey!
Be careful, my valiants!
Thank you, mother!
May Allah be with you, my Cerkutay.
Ayşe.
Aygül, why do you look sad?
You suffered a lot, now it's time to
be happy.
Don't forget your promise.
Don't be upset.
Even if you are upset...
...Cerkutay will find a way
to make you smile.
Thank you, mother.
I just got overwhelmed.
Keep your heart relaxed, my girl.
They will return safe and sound.
I hope.
Come on.
Welcome, Kosses.
I've been in this castle
ever since I can remember.
Gündüz Bey.
Welcome to you.
I got this castle from your friend,
Nikola.
Not from you.
A took it with blood.
Right, I forgot.
You and Nikola are the same.
You are those who stab
their friends on their backs.
I never did.
What happened with my brother doesn't
concern you.
Know your place.
Your visit is over...
...Gündüz Bey.
I can't do anything to you right now
because of the situation.
Pray that you've been a friend
to my brother.
You can leave.
We will meet again, Kosses.
Come on, Valiants!
Soldiers!
Osman chose a decent place for himself.
This place sees everywhere.
It is safe from ambushes.
But this time, we are superior
than nature.
The first to come claims his enemy.
Bravo! Scholar Geyhatu, bravo!
You are correct.
But there is a slight incorrectness.
Because we were here first.
And Rogatus Laskaris,
from Laskaris Dynasty!
What happened, Geyhatu?
You look like you have seen a ghost!
He is pale, because he knows he is
living his last day.
I can't even see his eyes.
Lords talk well.
Their tongue works well.
However, their head doesn't work.
So you are going to die
with Osman.
I am at ease.
Your end will be harsh.
But your job at the other world
is even harsher.
Your grave waits for you Geyhatu.
Is this how you protect the
future of Turks, Osman?
What a shame.
Can a Bey who works with a Lord
found a state?
You united and trapped me.
Rogatus wake up!
I set up such a game that...
...you are not going to get rid of it.
You cannot corner someone who was born
on the horse, Osman.
We were born on the horse too!
We ate meat...
We rided horses.
But we have a supremacy against you.
We have been honored with Islam.
Then you are going to die with your honor.
We are as large as the world, Osman.
There is no land that doesn't belong
to Genghis Khan.
Every land waits for its time.
Until you face us.
You are going to die.
And the ones who follow you too.
The dominance of this world
is Turks'!
You can't even protect what you have.
How can you set your eyes on the world?
I don't trust what I have in my hands...
I trust what I have in my heart.
Samarkand, Konya, even Otuken
The breed of Genghis rules
everywhere you think yours.
God lives in the time.
Humans were born to die.
Do not forget the lose you had.
You are not as strong as before.
I neither die with a trap...
Nor Mongols wipe out with a lose.
The poison is kicking in.
Osman, you proved your cowardness.
You poisoned the ones whom
you cannot beat.
However, if you kill me, 20,000 Mongol
soldiers will destroy you.
Everyone who is trying to stop my brother
is here.
Mongols will fall one by one.
What can I want more?
Come on valiants, let's go.
Attack!
So you poisoned the soldiers.
I would poison you too Osman...
...if I had known you were working with
the Lords!
Soldiers, get ready!
Allah is eternal!
Alps!
Follow Geyhatu! Come on!
Come on hurry!
Osman Bey follows Geyhatu.
We'll kill them.
Geyhatu!
Where are you running Geyhatu?
Attack!
A Sultan should kill Geyhatu!
Who the hell are you, shepherd?
Here is your death.
You are going to die Geyhatu.
You will die in pain.
My Bey!
Let me help my Bey.
Geyhatu, your turn will come too!
Who are you?
Who are you serving?
I care the future of Turks!
You were the one who worked with Vizier...
...and tried to kill Beys who didn't obey.
Do you care the future of Turks
by killing them?
I will crush everyone until
I get to my objective!
What is your objective.
It is to kill you for now, Osman.
Come.
Attack!
Ya Allah!
Geyhatu.
Rogatus.
Boran alp.
I am sorry for your wife.
Osman Bey, I am dying for real this time.
But...
My heart is fresh.
I am on the right side.
Geyhatu.
Where is Geyhatu?
We are here to kill Geyhatu!
Where is he?
Of course! He saw us.
He must die now.
- Let's find him!
- Come on!
Hurry!
Turgut Bey! Follow Geyhatu!
Turgut Bey!
No one shall leave!
We have things to settle!
Vizier.
Please contact us for any inquiries
turkision@gmail.com